Aguinaldo Pedro

Email: aguinaldopedro.ap@gmail.com

Address: Plantgatan 4A, 214 27 Malmö, Sweden

Phone: 0709300891

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aguinaldo-pedro-17730634/

Objective

Proactive, team player and results-oriented with about 20 years' experience in the maritime industry. Adaptable, highly motivated, a fast learner and a doer who easily can turn words into actions. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills and can effectively work in a culturally diverse environment.

Experience

Head of Commercial Department

Sonangol Shipping Luanda, Angola September 2017 – November 2018 Analyzing the business performance, including the profitability, revenue, pricing and cost. Managing budgets, expenses and pricing and commercial arrangements. Price negotiations for commercial contracts.

Chartering Specialist

Stena Sonangol Suezmax Pool Houston, Texas April 2012 – August 2017 Responsible for the commercial management of pool vessels. Monitor market conditions and negotiate chartering rates for pool vessels, thus adding value and enhancing pool profitability

Commercial Operations

Stena Sonangol Suezmax Pool Houston, Texas November 2009 – April 2012 Responsible for the commercial operation of pools vessels. Maintaining and updating vessels voyage program. Liaising with shipping agents, charterers and brokers. Ensuring invoices are issued, approved and paid. Responsible for arranging bunkers

Merchant Marine Deck Officer (Tankers)

Sonangol Marine Services
Houston, Texas
December 2005 – November 2009

As a Third Officer, responsible for maintaining lifesaving and fire-fighting equipment and navigation watchkeeping duties. As a Second Officer, responsible for ships navigation equipment, ship's hospital, passage planning, maintaining lifesaving equipment and watchkeeping duties.

Sea Training (Cadetship)

Sonangol Marine Services Houston, Texas January 2000 – December 2005 School and Sea Training.

Security Personnel

Up FrontGlasgow, Scotland
November 2001 – May 2002

Security Watch at various retail shops and bars.

Teacher

Primary School 225 Luanda, Angola February 1998 – December 1999 Subjects Taught - Math / Science / Language

Education

Master in Shipping Management and Logistics

World Maritime University

Malmo, Sweden.

2019

Bachelor of Science in Business Finance

University of Phoenix

Houston, Texas 2017

Associate Degree in Business Foundation

University of Phoenix

Houston, Texas 2014

HND-Post

Glasgow College of Nautical Studies

Glasgow, Scotland 2006

Higher National Diploma

Glasgow College of Nautical Studies

Houston, Texas 2002

HND

Academy of Maritime Education and Training

Chennai, India

2001

Professional Training/Courses

- Specialized training Program for oil Tanker
- Training in Fire Prevention and fire Fighting
- Advanced Fire Fighting
- Medical first aid
- Proficiency in Survival Craft and Rescue Boats
- Personal Social Responsibilities
- Ship Security Officer
- Ship Maintenance and management System
- Maritime Resource Management
- ISM Code Internal Auditors
- Proficiency in Medical First Aid Aboard Ship
- Proficiency in Personal Safety & Social responsibilities

- Certificate in Chartering
- Bunkering Experience
- SP1-CGBR12: International Oil Supply, Transportation, Refining and Trading
- TD2-AGBR12 Tanker Ownership, Chartering and Operations
- Negotiations Skills

Skills

- Ship Chartering
- Ship Commercial Operation
- Negotiation
- Listening
- Communication
- Goal- Oriented
- Team-Player

Languages

• Portuguese

Native

• English

Advanced

• Spanish

Beginner